Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Haiti Grassroots Watch Archived Website, Oct 13, 2011-Jan 12, 2014; Haiti Grassroots Watch
  Haiti Grassroots Watch operates as a "watchdog" website which produces text, video, and audio content on the aid and reconstruction of Haiti from the point of view of the Haitian majority. The website provides updates and critique on the reconstruction efforts, as well as structural causes and challenges. Haiti Grassroots Watch is a collaboration of two Haitian grassroots media organizations, Groupe Medialternatif/Alterpresse and the Society for the Animation of Social Communication (SAKS), along with two networks – the network of women community radio broadcasters (REFRAKA) and the Association of Haitian Community Media (AMEKA), which is comprised of community radio stations located across Haiti.
  Haiti; Human rights -- Haïti.
- HARLEM FIGHTBACK AGAINST WAR AT HOME & ABROAD Archived Website, May 28, 2012- ongoing; Harlem Fight Back
  Harlem Fightback Against War at Home and Abroad is a Harlem based protest group. The website is their blog highlighting action alerts.
  African Americans -- Civil rights.
- Highlander Research and Education Center Archived Website, Jun 23, 2011- ongoing; Highlander Education and Research Center
  The Highlander Research and Education Center was created in1932 (as the Highlander Folk School) by Myles Horton and Don West in Grundy County, Tennessee, to serve as a grassroots organizing and movement building organization in Appalachia and the South that supported racial justice and the labor movement. They work with people fighting for economic and social justice, against environmental degradation. Through popular education, participatory research, and cultural work Highlander works to give people the ability to develop leadership and help create and support strong, democratic organizations.
  Community organization |z United States.; Radicalism -- Southern States; Social justice -- Southern States; Labor movement |z Southern States.; Civil rights |z Southern States.
- Housing Conservation Coordinators Archived Website, Apr 17, 2013 - ongoing; Housing Conservation Coordinators
  Housing Conservation Coordinators is a not-for-profit organization based in Clinton/Hell's Kitchen that seeks to preserve safe and affordable housing, advance social and economic justice, and fight for the rights of poor, low-income and working individuals and families. They provide services such as legal representation, tenant and community organizing, installation of energy efficient systems through their Weatherization Program, and technical training courses. The website contains information on legal and community services.
  Low-income housing.
- Housing is a Human Right Archived Website, Mar 4, 2012 - ongoing; http://housingisahumanright.org
  Housing is a Human Right is a multimedia project to record people's experiences trying to obtain or maintain housing. The website contains stories in many multimedia forms, including audio recordings, videos, and written accounts.
  Housing. Low-income tenants.
- I Am Mike Brown Archived Website, Dec 10, 2014-ongoing; I am Mike Brown
  Collected livestream coverage of protests and events following the murder of unarmed African-American teenager Mike Brown by Darren Wilson, a Ferguson, MO police officer in 2014.
- Immigrant Solidarity Network Archived Website, Sep 30, 2007 - ongoing; Immigrant Solidarity Network
  The National Immigrant Solidarity Network (NISN) is a coalition of immigrant rights, labor, human rights, religious, and student activist organizations from across the United States. The network organizes action and letter-writing campaigns and publishes immigration related news and organizes conferences and mobilizations.
- In Defence of Marxism Archived Website, Dec 11, 2008- ongoing; International Marxist Tendency (Organization)
  This is the website of the International Marxist Tendency, a Trotskyist organization, with roots in Great Britain.
  Trotskyism.; Communism.
- International Bolshevik Tendency (IBT) Archived Website, May 9, 2011- ongoing; International Bolshevik Tendency (Organization)
  The International Bolshevik Tendency (IBT) is a revolutionary socialist organization founded by former cadres of the international Spartacist tendency (today the International Communist League). They work in solidarity with the Revolutionary Tendency of the Socialist Workers Party to defend the revolutionary program against the centrist objectivism of the majority. They stand on the Trotskyist positions defended and elaborated by the revolutionary Spartacist League. The website contains their publication, 1917, other publications, articles, and other materials.
  Trotskyism -- United States.
- International Communist League (Fourth Internationalist) Archived Website, Nov 26, 2008- ongoing; International Communist League (Fourth Internationalist)
  The International Communist League (Fourth Internationalist), founded 1998, is an international Trotskyist organization, "a proletarian, revolutionary and internationalist tendency committed to the task of building Leninist parties as national sections of a democratic- centralist international." The origins of the ICL are in the Spartacist League/U.S., which began as the Revolutionary Tendency in the Socialist Workers Party and was bureaucratically expelled in 1963. The ICL publishes the periodicals, Workers Vanguard and The Spartacist. The website also contains periodicals, a directory, and other literature.
  Trotskyism.; Communism.; Trotsky, Leon, 1879-1940
- International Freedom of Expression Exchange Archived Website, Oct 15, 2011- ongoing; International Freedom of Expression eXchange Network
  International Freedom of Expression eXchange Network, created in 1992 in Montreal works to expose violations of free expression around the world and promote free expression. The website publishes news and runs advocacy campaigns. IFEX's positions are based upon the principles of Article 19 of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. IFEX numbers 95 independent organizations worldwide and is managed by the Canadian Journalists for Free Expression (CJFE).
  News web sites |z United States.; Freedom of speech -- United States.; Human rights.
- International Publishers Archived Website, Apr 28, 2012- ongoing; International Publishers
  International Publishers is a publishing house historically associated with the Communist Party USA that publishes working class literature. The website contains an online catalog.
  Publishers and publishing; Communism.
- International Socialist Organization Archived Website, Nov 20, 2008- ongoing; International Socialist Organization (U.S.)
  The International Socialist Organization (U.S.), founded 1969, is a Trotskyist organization, and publishes Labor Notes, a national voice for progressive rank and file unionists (http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1862bf8f), the Socialist Worker and the International Socialist Review. Members are involved in helping to build a number of struggles: the movement to stop the war on Iraq, fights against racism and anti-immigrant scapegoating, the struggle for women's rights like the right to choose abortion, opposing anti-gay bigotry, and standing up for workers' rights. The website contains links to their publications, information on their branches, resources for socialists, and other materials.
  Trotskyism.; Communism.; Socialism
- Jacobin Magazine Archived Website, Sep 22, 2014-ongoing; Jacobin Magazine
  Jacobin is a print and online magazine focusing on news and commentary on the American left, offering socialist perspectives on politics, economics, and culture. The print magazine is released quarterly and reaches over 6,000 subscribers, in addition to a web audience of 400,000 a month.
  Socialism -- Periodicals.; Alternative mass media |z United States.; Jacobin (New York, N.Y.)
- Jews for Racial & Economic Justice (U.S.) Archived Website, Sep 29, 2007- ongoing; Jews for Racial & Economic Justice (U.S.)
  Jews for Racial and Economic Justice (JFREJ) is a membership-based organization founded in 1990 that engages Jews to pursue and win racial and economic justice including via systemic changes, in partnership with people of color, low-income, and immigrant communities in New York City.
  Jews |z New York (State) |z New York |x Social conditions.; Jews |z New York (State) |z New York |x Political activity.
- KPFT 90.1 FM Archived Website, Jul 17, 2011- ongoing; KPFT-FM (Radio station: Houston, Tex.)
  KPFT 90.1 FM is a Pacfica Foundation radio station, located in Los Angeles, California. KPFT was founded by journalist Larry Lee in 1970 in Houston.
- Labor Party (U.S.) Archived Website, Feb 7, 2007 - ongoing; Labor Party (U.S.)
  The South Carolina Labor Party, founded in June 1996 at a convention of 1,400 delegates from hundreds of local and international unions as well as individual activists. The Labor Party platform includes issues such as healthcare and the rights to organize, bargain, and strike. They attempt to run candidates in South Carolina.
  Third parties (United States politics); Labor movement -- Political activity -- United States.
- Labor Upfront Newsletter Archived Website, Mar 9, 2010-Mar 23, 2013; Communist Party of the United States of America. Labor Commission
  Labor Upfront Newsletter is the online publication of the Labor Commission of the Communist Party, USA, which directs the Party's work in the labor movement.
  Communism -- United States.; Commission.; Labor unions and communism -- United States.
- League for Industrial Democracy Archived Website, Dec 6, 2012; League for Industrial Democracy
  This website is the site for the contemporary League for Industrial Democracy, descended from the League founded in 1905 by Upton Sinclair, Jack London, Clarence Darrow, Norman Thomas and other writers and civic leaders. The League for Industrial Democracy was an American educational organization dedicated to increasing democracy in economic, political, and cultural life. The contemporary members of the League work for full racial equality, the abolition of poverty, the strengthening of trade unions and cooperatives, the expansion of civil liberties, the extension of public ownership and democratic economic planning, and the realignment of political organizations with a view toward making them more responsive to the will of the people. The website contains a blog and a forum.
  Labor -- United States.; Power resources -- United States.; Socialism -- United States.; Unemployed; Unemployed -- United States.; Right and left (Political science).
- League for the Revolutionary Party - Communist Organization for the Fourth International Archived Website, Aug 16, 2009- ongoing; League for the Revolutionary Party
  The League for the Revolutionary Party (LRP), based in the United States, is dedicated to the restoration of authentic Marxism and the political independence of the working class with an effort to recreate the Fourth International. They are affiliated with the Communist Organization for the Fourth International (COFI). They publish the political and theoretical magazine Proletarian Revolution. The LRP upholds the method of permanent revolution. The LRP aims to resurrect the method of Trotsky's Transitional Program. The website contains analysis on current events, theory, and translations of Marxist writers.
  Trotskyism -- United States.; Fourth International
- League of Revolutionaries for a New America Archived Website, May 19, 2011-ongoing; League of Revolutionaries for a New America
  The League of Revolutionaries for a New America, founded in 1993, is an organization of revolutionaries that advocate for an end the injustices of capitalism through the education of communism. Rally, Comrades! is the political paper of the League of Revolutionaries for a New America. Rally, Comrades! examines and analyzes the problems of the revolutionary movement, and draws political conclusions for the tasks of revolutionaries at each stage of the revolutionary process. The website contains articles on technology, the economy, politics, the revolution, communism, the corporate state, and other movements.
  Socialism -- United States.
- Left Forum Archived Website, May 7, 2010 - ongoing; Left Forum
  The Left Forum is an annual conference (in the spring), and is the successor to the Socialist Scholars Conference (SSC), established in 1981. Left Forum seeks to link the critique of neo-liberalism to anti-capitalism, and to foster radical alternatives to the established order. The conference is held at Pace University in New York City, and has over 3,000 participants, over 300 panels, and 1000 speakers, related to a chosen theme. The website contains information on conferences since 2007.
  Radicalism -- United States -- Congresses
- LeftShift.org Archived Website, Apr 20, 2009-Apr 12, 2013; LeftShift.org
  LeftShift.org was formed in June 2005 with the goal of showing solidarity with revolutionary Cuba against the ever-present imperialist threats from Washington, DC and Miami. Left Shift also tries to educate the US public about Cuba and its revolution, the nature of the threats against it, and opportunities for our visitors (audience) to get involved in the solidarity movement. While the current focus is Cuba, LeftShift.org stands in solidarity with all people under the gun of U.S. and U.S.-backed imperialism–from Afghanistan to Haiti to Iraq to Palestine to Venezuela–as well as communities under attack within the borders of the U.S.
  Cuba.; Anti-imperialist movements |z United States.
- Leon Trotsky Internet Archive Archived Website, Dec 23, 2008-ongoing; Trotsky Internet Archive
  The Leon Trotsky Internet Archive contains Trotsky's writings, biographical information, photographs, and other documents.
- Lesbian Herstory Archives Archived Website, Dec 9, 2011- ongoing; Lesbian Herstory Archives
  The Lesbian Herstory Archives is an archival collection of materials by and about lesbians and their communities. The Lesbian Herstory Archives exists to gather and preserve records of Lesbian lives and activities so that future generations will have ready access to materials relevant to their lives. The archive was founded in 1975, by Joan Nestle and Deborah Edel. The website lists the collections, publishes newsletters, and information about exhibits. The website also has information on how to donate to the archive.
  Feminism |x Archival resources.
- Liberation Road Archived Website, October 2019-ongoing
  Liberation Road, formerly Freedom Road Socialist Organization/Organicion Socialista del Camino Para la Libertad (FRSO/OSCL), was founded in 1985 when two small organizations, Proletarian Unity League (PUL) and the Revolutionary Workers Headquarters (RWH) merged. They are a network of revolutionary organizers that work to fight white supremacist capitalism. They work in the Black and Chicano movements and various immigrants' struggles, and in labor unions, workers centers and labor/community groups and coalitions. The website contains information on their platform and news and analysis. In April 2019, the organization changed its name to Liberation Road.
- Links International Journal of Socialist Renewal Archived Website, Jul 2, 2011- ongoing; Links International Journal of Socialist Renewal
  Links International Journal of Socialist Renewal is an academic journal for the Left in the post-Cold War era. The journal aims to foster discussion and dialogue between Marxists and socialists from different political traditions. It seeks to bring together those in the international left who are opposed to neoliberal economic and social policies, and reject the bureaucratic model of "socialism" that arose in the Soviet Union, Eastern Europe and China. The publishers promote a socialism that's green, feminist and anti-racism. The website contains articles, past issues of the publication, and news listings.
  Socialism -- Periodicals.
- Living Liberally Archived Website, Dec 24, 2008 - ongoing; Living Liberally
  Living Liberally, founded in 2003 by David Alpert and Justin Krebs, provides an entrance into progressive involvement, using social interaction to promote political action. Living Liberally is built upon networks of local gatherings. These projects include: Drinking Liberally, a national network of social clubs; Laughing Liberally, a political comedy project; Screening Liberally, a politically-conscious film series; and Reading Liberally, a book tour of progressive authors.
- Make Wall Street Pay Archived Website, Oct 14, 2011-Oct 13, 2013; National Peoples Action
  Make Wall Street Pay is a campaign supported by National People Action. The campaign gives Americans the means to air grievances toward corporate banks and calls for banks to pay their fair share. The website contains "bills" sent by users posted to the website addressed to the banks.
  Distributive justice.; Social responsibility in banking.
- Maoist Internationalist Movement (MIM) Archived Website, Jul 23, 2010- ongoing; Maoist Internationalist Movement
  This is an archive of the former website of the Maoist Internationalist Movement, which was run by the now defunct Maoist Internationalist Party - Amerika. The MIM now consists of many independent cells, many of which have their own indendendent organs both online and off. MIM(Prisons) serves these documents as a service to and reference for the anti-imperialist movement worldwide. Also archived herein is a collection of revolutionary art hosted by MIM.
  Maoism -- United States.; Maoism.
- Margert Community Corporation Archived Website, Mar 16, 2012 - ongoing; Margert Community Corporation
  Margert Community Corporation is a nonprofit, community-based organization and is a New York State Division of Housing and Community Renewal (DHCR) approved housing counseling agency that has been providing neighborhood preservation services, housing assistance, and housing counseling to low-income tenants and homeowners, the elderly, and persons with disabilities since 1980. Their primary service area is Far Rockaway, Queens. The website contains a calendar, photos, news, and housing counseling.
  Housing.
- Marxism Leninism Today Archived Website, Nov 2, 2010- ongoing; Marxism-Leninism Today
  Marxism-Leninism Today is an electronic journal containing articles and commentaries on the theory and practice of Marxism-Leninism; contemporary dialectical and historical materialism. Its goal is to be a resource where Marxist-Leninists can discuss and apply their science to all fields of study. It contains articles that are of particular interest to Marxist scholars, both Communist and non-Communist. Topics include philosophy, religion, African American history, labor history, trade union strategy, Marxist historiography, book reviews, and other articles. The website contains articles which can be browsed by topic.
  Marxism |z United States |v Periodicals.; Communism -- Periodicals.; Marxism-Leninism Today
- Marxist Education Press Publications Archived Website, May 1, 2012-Nov 1, 2012; Marxist Educational Press
  Marxist Education Press (MEP) was a publishing house, publishing academic books and a quarterly journal, Nature, Society, and Thought. The website contains a book catalog, journal articles, and book descriptions. MEP is no longer active.
- Marxist-Humanist Initiative Archived Website, Jan 8, 2010- ongoing; Marxist-Humanist Initiative
  Marxist-Humanist Initiative (MHI) began in April 2009 and is a collective that aims to contribute to the transformation of this capitalist world by developing the philosophy of Karl Marx (1818-1883) and Raya Dunayevskaya (1910-1987). The website contains their principles and by-laws, their publication, "With Sober Senses," event listings, and other writings and publications.
  Communism -- United States.; Communism.; Humanism.; Dunayevskaya, Raya
- Metropolitan Council on Housing Archived Website, Mar 5, 2012 - ongoing; Metropolitan Council on Housing (New York, N.Y.)
  The Metropolitan Council on Housing, founded in 1959, is a membership organization dedicated to preserving and expanding New York City's supply of affordable housing. Met Council focuses on preserving rental housing and strengthening tenants' rights. They work through grassroots organizing, lobbying, direct action, including rent strikes, and public education. Met Council has a monthly newspaper (TENANT), a weekly call-in radio show ("Housing Notebook"), forums, and a volunteer-staffed tenant hotline.
- Million Hoodies Movement for Justice Archived Website, Jul 16, 2013- ongoing; Million Hoodies Movement for Justice
  The Million Hoodies Movement for Justice is a national non-profit with over 50,000 members working to protect and empower young people of color from racial profiling and gun violence. The organization was founded in response to the fatal shooting of Trayvon Martin by George Zimmerman on February 26, 2012. The organization is named for the hooded sweatshirt Martin wore when he was shot. The organization works through demonstrations and lobbying. The website contains event listings, curated music for the organization and actions, and a blog.
  Racial profiling in law enforcement -- United States.; Discrimination |z United States.; Martin, Trayvon, 1995-2012
- Millions March NYC Archived Website, Dec 10, 2014-ongoing; Millions March NYC
  The Millions March NYC was a march on December 13th 2014, which was part of a national "Day of Anger" in response to the police murders of Mike Brown, Eric Garner, Tamir Rice and Akai Gurley in 2014. The website includes logistical information about the march, as well as the demands of the Black Lives Matter movement.
  Grand jury |z United States.; New York (N.Y.).; Police brutality.; Black power.
- Monthly Review: An Independent Socialist Magazine Archived Website, Aug 2, 2009- ongoing; Monthly Review
  The Monthly Review (MR), founded in May 1949 by Paul Sweezy and Leo Huberman, is an independent socialist periodical. The review aims to publish stories on current events framed from a socialist point of view. The review also established a web magazine, MRZine in 2006, which updates daily. MR also has a book press, and a blog, Reflections of Fidel.
  Socialism -- United States -- Periodicals.; Publishers and publishing -- United States.; Monthly Review (New York, N.Y.)
- NARAL Pro-Choice America Archived Website, Jul 23, 2012- ongoing; National Abortion and Reproductive Rights Action League
  National Abortion Rights Action League (NARAL) Pro-Choice America is an organization in the United States that engages in political action to oppose restrictions on abortion and expand access to abortion. They work through lobbying, electing pro-choice lawmakers, and educate on women's rights. Their website contains news, personal accounts, action alerts, and multimedia.
  Pro-choice movement.; Reproductive rights -- United States; Pro-choice movement -- United States.
- NARAL Pro-Choice New York Archived Website, Apr 9, 2014-ongoing; National Abortion Rights Action League, New York State
  NARAL Pro-Choice New York is a political and advocacy organization, whose mission is to guarantee every woman the right to make personal decisions regarding the full range of reproductive choices, including preventing unintended pregnancy, bearing healthy children, and choosing legal abortion. The website contains information on current and past projects, political endorsements, training manuals, reports, and news and event listings.
  Pro-choice movement -- United States.
- National Action Network Archived Website, Aug 26, 2013- ongoing; National Action Network